// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "This is a communicative strategy that we use when we want to establish a topic in a conversation.",
    answer: "A. nomination",
    options: [
      "A. nomination",
      "B. restriction",
      "C. turn-taking",
      "D. topic-control"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "It is a communicative strategy used to end a conversation.",
    answer: "A. termination",
    options: [
      "A. termination",
      "B. topic-shifting",
      "C. topic-control",
      "D. repair"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "It involves moving from one topic to another.",
    answer: "B. topic-shifting",
    options: [
      "A. termination",
      "B. topic-shifting",
      "C. topic-control",
      "D. repair"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "This strategy is used to address the problems encountered in a conversation.",
    answer: "D. repair",
    options: [
      "A. termination",
      "B. topic-shifting",
      "C. topic-control",
      "D. repair"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "This strategy limits what a speaker can say to avoid ideas that are unnecessary and irrelevant to the topic.",
    answer: "B. restriction",
    options: [
      "A. nomination",
      "B. restriction",
      "C. turn-taking",
      "D. topic-control"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "During group discussion, the leader asks everyone to brainstorm about the possible topics for the group research. What communicative strategy is employed?",
    answer: "A. nomination",
    options: [
      "A. nomination",
      "B. restriction",
      "C. turn-taking",
      "D. topic-control"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Hearings in the Senate usually include oral testimony from witnesses followed by questioning of the witnesses by members of Congress. Which communicative strategy is employed in the above procedure?",
    answer: "C. topic-control",
    options: [
      "A. termination",
      "B. topic-shifting",
      "C. topic-control",
      "D. repair"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Every time your group conducts a meeting, nothing is accomplished because the time is used up due to irrelevant and unnecessary topics that intervene the discussion. As the group leader, how will you keep your members focused on the agenda of the meeting using the restriction strategy?",
    answer: "C. Give instructions before the meeting starts to confine and limit what they can say.",
    options: [
      "A. Tell them that they will get kicked out from the group if they will not cooperate.",
      "B. End the meeting immediately as soon as the group begins to talk about other things irrelevant to the agenda.",
      "C. Give instructions before the meeting starts to confine and limit what they can say.",
      "D. Show disappointment."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following responses uses repair as communicative strategy?",
    answer: "C. 'Excuse me, can you please repeat the question?'",
    options: [
      "A. 'Best regards to your family! See you around.'",
      "B. 'Please enlighten me about the solution to the issue you are suggesting.'",
      "C. 'Excuse me, can you please repeat the question?'",
      "D. 'By the way, I need a few personal details about yourself.'"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which of these shows turn-taking strategy?",
    answer: "D. 'Group 1 will talk about the advantages of technology while group 2 will talk about its disadvantages.'",
    options: [
      "A. 'I will hear your suggestion after you listen to my plan.'",
      "B. 'Ok, I am listening. Go on.'",
      "C. 'Precisely! That is a very good reason why we need to come up with a contingency plan.'",
      "D. 'Group 1 will talk about the advantages of technology while group 2 will talk about its disadvantages.'"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Among these statements, which can be used for topic shifting?",
    answer: "C. 'Wait. Before I forget to tell you, did you know we have a new classmate?'",
    options: [
      "A. 'Did you know that washing your hands with soap for 20 seconds will protect you from Corona virus?'",
      "B. 'Let’s call it a day. We can all go home.'",
      "C. 'Wait. Before I forget to tell you, did you know we have a new classmate?'",
      "D. 'I would like to clarify two things regarding the announcement that I had made.'"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Everyone wants to talk. They all want their opinion to be heard. What would be the most appropriate response to give everybody equal opportunity to talk?",
    answer: "B. 'Everyone, please calm down.'",
    options: [
      "A. 'We will definitely go nowhere with all of you talking all at once!'",
      "B. 'Everyone, please calm down.'",
      "C. 'All I can hear is noise.'",
      "D. 'Everyone will be heard. Let’s begin with you, Nathan.'"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "You are reporting in front of the class and you sense that your classmates did not understand the last part that you’ve just said. Which of the following responses best addresses the issue?",
    answer: "B. 'Let me say it once again... This is what I mean...'",
    options: [
      "A. 'I am sorry if you did not get my point, but we need to move on to the next topic.'",
      "B. 'Let me say it once again... This is what I mean...'",
      "C. 'I hope everybody understood what I said.'",
      "D. 'I am wasting my time with all of you.'"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "You are talking to Sheila for half an hour now and you notice that her responses are beginning to get short and most of them are just nods and smile. How would you end your conversation with her?",
    answer: "C. 'Thank you for your time. It’s nice talking with you. See you next time.'",
    options: [
      "A. 'Did I bore you with my stories?'",
      "B. 'This is what I really wish to say...'",
      "C. 'Thank you for your time. It’s nice talking with you. See you next time.'",
      "D. 'I understand that you are not interested anymore. I’ll just go.'"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "You want to make a conversation with the new student in your class. Which is the best way to establish a topic?",
    answer: "C. 'I have heard that you are from Bicol. I think the beaches there are great.'",
    options: [
      "A. 'Why did you transfer to our school?'",
      "B. 'Do you want to join our club?'",
      "C. 'I have heard that you are from Bicol. I think the beaches there are great.'",
      "D. 'Can I talk to you?'"
    ]
  },
];
